Guide to the B'nai B'rith Collection of post Civil War pamphlets, 1868-1872
Department of Special Collections
B'nai B'rith Collection of post Civil War pamphlets,
1868-1872
M1031
B'nai B'rith
.25 linear ft. (10 pamphlets)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
This collection of 10 pamphlets reflects Jewish activities in the B'nai B'rith lodges of Chicago, Cleveland, Nashville, and New York.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1998.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
This group of ten pamphlets offers a first-hand glimpse into the functioning of B'nai B'rith lodges in America in the immediate post-Civil War period. Jewish activity in cities from Chicago to Nashville are detailed and documented.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Jews--United States--History--1789-1945.
Collection Contents
- Proceedings of District Grand Lodge, No. 2, Independent Order for the Year 1871, including the Twentieth Anuual Meeting held in St. Louis, MO on January 21, 1872 and following days. -- Cincinnati: A. Abraham, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Proceedings of District Grand Lodge, No. 2, Independent Order for the Year 1869 including the Eighteenth Annual Meeting held in Nashville, Tennessee on January 16, 1870 and the following days. -- Cincinnati: Robert Clarke & Co., Printers, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Orphan Asylum of District No. 2, I.O.B.B. at Cleveland, Ohio. Inaugurated July 14th, 1868. -- New York: Lithographing, Engraving, and Printing Co., 1868 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Third Annual Report of the Board of Trustees of the Orphan Asylum, Dist. nos. 2 & 6, I.O.B.B. at Cleveland, Ohio, for Year ending October 1, 1871. -- Cincinnati: Bloch & Co., Steam Book and Job Printers and Lithographers, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Proceedings of the General Convention of the Independent Order B'nai B'rith, held in the City of New York, July 19-27, 1868 (5628). -- New York: Lithographing, Engraving and Printing Co., 1868 (5628) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1871 Third Annual report of District Grand Lodge no. 6, I.O.B.B. -- Chicago: Franz Gindele, Steam Book and Job Printer, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- General Bericht der Districts - Grossloge No. 1, U.O.B.B. in New York ... von October 1862, bis Ende ... 1868-1869. -- New York: [s.n.], 1870 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Report of the Executive Committee of the Constitution Grand Lodge, I.O.B.B., August 1868-January 1870. -- New York: [s.n.], 1870 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- General Bericht der Districts - Grossloge No. 1, U.O.B.B. in New York, 1869-1870. -- New York: [s.n.], 1870 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- General Bericht der Districts - Grossloge No. 1, U.O.B.B. in New York, Januar 1870 Enbe Januar 1871. -- New York: [s.n.], 1871 (Box 1, Folder 10)